we need to
modify the code that we've been given so
that it iterates five times
if we run the code as it's been given to
us you can see that
right now it iterates only once and
that's because
our break statement on line five will
always be executed
there's no condition associated with
this break
so the way the code is currently written
we're only able to iterate through the
loop one time
before encountering the break statement
and exiting the block
now you can see that on line one a local
variable iterations has been initialized
and references the integer one
we can use this variable to keep track
of our iterations
as we loop through this code we can
increment iterations by one
and remember that this syntax is just
shorthand
for reassignment
[Music]
now that we have a way to keep track of
our number of iterations
we can add a condition to this break on
line six
your first instinct may be to break if
iterations is equal to five let's run
that code and see what it looks like
we only iterated through the loop four
times
if you look at this code closely you can
determine why that is
when we increment the value of
iterations from four to five
on line five line 6 will break out of
this block
when iterations is equal to 5 prior to
ever outputting that we've reached our
fifth iteration
so instead we can use a different
comparison and break when iterations
is greater than five and with our code
written this way
we will break out of our block after
outputting that our number of iterations
is five
we'll increment iterations to six on
line five
and then break out of the block so let's
run our code and see what it looks like
now
and this is the result we were looking
for
so it's important to always pay close
attention when you're
looping through a block to make sure
that you're using the
appropriate comparison operator to
determine when to break out of your loop
now you may also be aware of some ruby
methods that
allow you to achieve the same result
but you won't always have every method
memorized and it's important to know the
basics
of looping and how to write out logic on
your own
if you're not aware of a method that can
do it for you
you